ALL CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS, EVENTS, AND LOCATIONS IN THIS SHOW ARE FICTITIOUS
모든 캐릭터, 조직, 이벤트, 이 쇼의 위치는 허구입니다.
EPISODE 14
에피소드 14
PROFESSOR SEO IN-HO
서인호 교수
Mom.
엄마.
Eun-seo!
은서!
Are you treating me because it's payday?
월급날이라 대접하는 거야?
Of course. It'll be a full-course meal, including dessert.
물론. 풀코스 식사가 되겠지만, 디저트 포함.
What are we eating?
우리는 무엇을 먹고 있나요?
Let's see. Beef?
어디 보자. 소고기?
Sounds good?
좋은 것 같나요?
Why isn't she picking up?
그녀는 왜 전화를 받지 않는 걸까요?
Did something urgent come up?
급한 일이라도 생겼나요?
Who are you calling like that?
누구한테 그렇게 전화하는 거야?
It's the hospital.
병원이에요.
I guess you're nervous that Seung-hi is in charge of my mother.
승희가 긴장했나봐 우리 엄마를 책임져요.
What are you on about?
지금 무슨 일을 하고 계시나요?
Someone might hear you.
누군가 당신의 말을 들을 수도 있습니다.
You listen carefully.
당신은주의 깊게 들어요.
My mother may find out one day but now is not the time.
엄마가 언젠가는 알게 될지도 몰라 하지만 지금은 그럴 때가 아니다.
If you make a mistake and my mother finds out about our divorce
실수를 하면 그리고 우리 엄마가 우리 이혼 사실을 알게 됐어
before she's treated and discharged, then…
치료받고 퇴원하기 전에는…
I won't hold back.
나는 주저하지 않을 것이다.
Of course. But we haven't gotten a divorce.
물론. 하지만 우리는 이혼하지 않았습니다.
Welcome.
환영.
There you are.
거기 있습니다.
-Hello. -Hey.
-안녕하세요. -여기요.
Mother, you're here.
어머니, 여기 계셨습니다.
Yes, I feel bad for bothering you when you're so busy.
응, 귀찮게 해서 미안해 너무 바쁠 때.
No, it's fine.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
Even busier people do at least this much for their families.
바쁜 사람들도 그렇겠지만 적어도 가족에게는 이 정도입니다.
-Let's go in, Mother. Let's go, Mom. -Okay.
-들어가세요, 어머니. 가자, 엄마. -좋아요.
Eun-seo, you have to eat a lot today, okay?
은서야 밥먹어야지 오늘은 많이, 알았지?
Do you see this? I'm wearing elastic pants.
이거 보이나요? 신축성 있는 바지를 입고 있어요.
Okay, let's eat until those pants rip.
알았어, 바지가 찢어질 때까지 먹자.
How dare you try to seduce my man?
어떻게 감히 내 남자를 유혹하려고 합니까?
-Mother! -No!
-어머니! -아니요!
-There must have been a misunderstanding! -Mother!
-오해가 있었나봐요! -어머니!
-You must be mistaken!
-당신이 착각한 게 틀림없어요!
Please let go of her! Let go first, and we can talk.
그녀를 놓아주세요! 먼저 놔두고 얘기하자.
Ma'am, let go of her hand first.
부인, 먼저 손을 놓으세요.
-Are you okay? -What do we do?
-괜찮으세요? -우리는 무엇을 하나요?
Mother?
어머니?
Look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
So you're the son who had an affair and raised a secret love child?
그럼 당신은 바람피운 아들이군요 그리고 비밀스러운 사랑의 아이를 키웠나요?
Be quiet!
조용히 하세요!
No, Ms. Oh. It's not what you think!
아니요, 오 선생님. 그것은 당신이 생각하는 것이 아니다!
Please cover your ears!
귀를 막아주세요!
Like mother like son, both of you are cheaters!
엄마같은 아들같은, 너희 둘 다 사기꾼이야!
Is it in your genes?
당신의 유전자에 있습니까?
-Let go. -Please be quiet!
- 놔. -조용히 해주세요!
Ma'am, what did you just say?
아주머니, 방금 뭐라고 하셨나요?
Did you just say he had an affair and has a secret love child?
방금 그 사람이 바람을 피웠다고 말했나요? 비밀스러운 사랑의 아이가 있나요?
Yes!
예!
He had an affair with his first love and has a daughter.
그는 첫사랑과 바람을 피웠다 그리고 딸이 있어요.
Did you not know?
몰랐나요?
Welcome.
환영.
Gosh, Grandma.
이런, 할머니.
Goodness.
선량.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Ms. Kwak.
곽씨.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Hey, let's go.
이봐, 가자.
Go where?
어디로 가나요?
Ms. Kwak.
곽씨.
I'll contact you soon. I'll explain everything then.
곧 연락드리겠습니다. 그럼 다 설명해줄게.
-Come on. -An affair is an affair!
-어서 해봐요. -불륜은 불륜이다!
What other explanation is needed?
무슨 다른 설명이 필요합니까?
Let go! I'm not going to stand back!
가자! 나는 물러서지 않을 것이다!
Wait.
기다리다.
Let's go out and talk for a minute.
잠깐 나가서 얘기 좀 하자.
Let go.
가자.
What are you two doing here?
너희 둘은 여기서 뭐하고 있는 거야?
We came to eat. Why else would we come here?
우리는 먹으러 왔습니다. 그렇지 않으면 우리가 왜 여기에 오겠습니까?
Just by coincidence?
그냥 우연히?
Did all of you know about this?
이 사실은 다들 알고 계셨나요?
Ms. Kwak.
곽씨.
Jung-min and I-rang too?
정민이랑 아이랑도요?
Jeong-suk, did you know too?
정숙씨도 알고 있었나요?
Mom.
엄마.
Mom…
엄마…
Where did In-ho go?
인호는 어디로 갔나요?
Of course it's by coincidence. Do you think we stalk you?
물론 우연이죠. 우리가 당신을 스토킹한다고 생각하시나요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
I'm all out of sorts right now.
나는 지금 모든 것이 엉망입니다.
But the situation here isn't great.
하지만 이곳의 상황은 좋지 않습니다.
I'm sorry, but can you go eat somewhere else?
죄송하지만 식사하러 가실 수 있나요? 다른 곳에?
Why should we do that?
왜 그렇게 해야 합니까?
-Seung-hi. -I don't want to hide anymore.
-승희. -더 이상 숨고 싶지 않아요.
I don't want to look pathetic in front of Eun-seo anymore.
한심하게 보이고 싶지 않아 이제 은서 앞에서.
If you go in there right now, you won't look pathetic.
지금 당장 거기로 들어가면, 당신은 한심해 보이지 않을 것입니다.
You'll look downright deplorable.
당신은 정말 한심해 보일 것입니다.
Seung-hi, Eun-seo, please.
승희, 은서씨 주세요.
Save me just this once, please?
이번 한 번만 저를 구해주세요.
Seo In-ho, you bastard. Where are you?
서인호, 이 새끼야. 어디세요?
Okay?
좋아요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Bye.
안녕.
Let us go to my place.
내 집으로 가자.
Does that include me?
나도 포함되나요?
Shall we go to another beef restaurant?
다른 쇠고기 식당으로 가볼까요?
No, let's change the menu. What do you want to eat?
아니, 메뉴를 바꾸자. 무엇을 먹고 싶나요?
Are you still dating Dad?
아직도 아빠랑 사귀세요?
You're not legally married and it's not like there's a custody issue.
당신은 법적으로 결혼하지 않았습니다 양육권 문제도 아닌 것 같고요.
So why are you still with him?
그런데 왜 아직도 그 사람과 함께 있어요?
Eun-seo.
은서.
You'll understand once you meet someone you like later on.
만나보면 이해하게 될 거야 나중에 좋아하는 사람.
These things aren't easy.
이런 일들은 쉽지 않습니다.
I understand that it isn't easy.
쉽지 않다는 것을 이해합니다.
Do you not want to eat?
먹고 싶지 않아?
I'm not in the mood to have a meal.
식사할 기분이 아니에요.
Let's go and let off some steam.
가서 화를 좀 내보자.
-It's so spicy. -It's spicy?
-너무 매워요. - 매워요?
You actually spend money on something this spicy?
실제로 돈을 쓴다 이렇게 매운 거?
You feel a sense of catharsis if you eat something this spicy.
카타르시스를 느끼는 것 같아요 이렇게 매운 걸 먹으면.
Mom, you shouldn't have any more. You had gastric cramps recently.
엄마, 더 이상은 안 돼요. 최근에 위경련이 있으셨어요.
It's okay. I'll have a little more.
괜찮아요. 조금 더 먹을게요.
This is actually kind of addictive.
이건 사실 일종의 중독성이에요.
-Right? -Yes.
-오른쪽? -예.
Mom.
엄마.
Let's go back to the US.
미국으로 돌아가자.
Let's go back
돌아가자
and start over.
그리고 다시 시작하세요.
You and me.
당신과 나.
Do you
당신은
really have a child out of wedlock?
정말 혼외 아이가 있나요?
I'm sorry, Mother.
죄송해요, 어머니.
I guess it's true since you're saying you're sorry.
내 생각엔 그게 사실인 것 같아 네가 미안하다고 말했으니까.
Who is the woman?
여자는 누구입니까?
That lady before said it was with your first love…
아까 그 아줌마가 말했지 너의 첫사랑과 함께였어...
Don't tell me…
말하지 마세요…
Is it the professor in charge of me?
내 담당 교수님이신가요?
Professor Choi Seung-hi?
최승희 교수님?
Mom…
엄마…
That's why you wanted me to switch doctors? Right?
그래서 당신은 나를 원했어요 의사를 바꾸려고? 오른쪽?
The truth is…
진실은…
I'm sorry, Mother.
죄송해요, 어머니.
What I did is unforgivable.
내가 한 일은 용서받을 수 없습니다.
These are the medicine and expensive cosmetics
이것들은 약이다 그리고 비싼 화장품
that your mother gave to me as gifts.
네 어머니가 나에게 선물로 주신 것.
Take them back.
다시 가져가세요.
But the cosmetics did nothing wrong--
하지만 화장품은 아무 문제가 없었습니다.
I thought it was strange
이상하다고 생각했어요
when your mother started giving me expensive gifts
네 엄마가 시작했을 때 나에게 값비싼 선물을 주다
because she never did anything like that before.
왜냐면 그녀는 그런 적이 없거든 전에는 그런 것.
But now I know that she bought these things for me
하지만 이제 난 알아 그 사람이 나한테 이런 것들을 사줬다고
because she felt guilty about what her son had done.
왜냐하면 그녀는 죄책감을 느꼈기 때문이다 자기 아들이 무슨 짓을 했는지에 대해서.
Do you think I can take and use these knowing that?
내가 받아줄 수 있을 것 같아? 그걸 알면서도 이걸 사용하는 건가요?
Mom.
엄마.
Mom, don't worry too much.
엄마, 너무 걱정하지 마세요.
We'll resolve all this one way or another.
우리는 이 모든 것을 어떤 식으로든 해결할 것입니다.
Exactly how will you resolve this?
이 문제를 정확히 어떻게 해결하시겠습니까?
I'm mad at you too.
나도 너한테 화났어.
You had surgery and barely survived.
수술을 받으셨고 간신히 살아남으셨습니다.
Why would you keep this bottled up?
왜 이걸 병에 담아 두겠어요?
You work in the same place as that woman!
그 여자랑 같은 곳에서 일하잖아!
You must have felt such fury every single day!
그런 분노를 느꼈나 봐요 매일!
Fine.
괜찮은.
It's pointless for me to say what's right and wrong now.
내가 말하는 것은 무의미하다 지금 무엇이 옳고 그른지.
But, In-ho.
그런데 인호야.
Yes, Mother.
네, 어머니.
People can make mistakes and do the wrong thing.
사람은 실수할 수 있다 그리고 잘못된 일을 합니다.
But…
하지만…
what separates humans from animals
인간이 동물과 다른 점
is that humans can repent for their sins and ask for forgiveness.
인간이 자신의 죄를 회개할 수 있다는 것입니다. 그리고 용서를 구하세요.
No matter what happens between you two,
두 사람 사이에 무슨 일이 일어나더라도
you should sincerely ask my daughter, whom you've hurt, for forgiveness.
내 딸에게 진심으로 물어보세요. 당신이 상처를 준 사람을 용서해주세요.
Mother, what I did was wrong.
어머니, 제가 한 일은 잘못되었습니다.
I'll spend the rest of my life reflecting and asking for forgiveness.
나는 남은 인생을 보낼 것이다 반성하고 용서를 구합니다.
Please help her change her mind.
그녀가 마음을 바꾸도록 도와주세요.
She wants to divorce me.
그녀는 나와 이혼하고 싶어합니다.
That matter is up to you two.
그 문제는 너희 둘에게 달려 있다.
Get up. I have to go to the hospital.
일어나세요. 병원에 가야 해요.
Go to the hospital?
병원에 가시나요?
I have to go to the hospital and get my things!
병원에 가야 해요 그리고 내 물건을 가져와!
Mom, you can't be discharged right now. Let's go tomorrow.
엄마, 지금은 퇴원하실 수 없어요. 내일 가자.
You deal with the procedures.
절차를 처리합니다.
I want to sleep comfortably in my own home.
편안하게 자고 싶어 내 집에서.
Let's hear the results before you get discharged.
결과를 들어보자 퇴원하기 전에.
If you were me, would you want to stay here?
당신이 나라면, 여기 머물고 싶니?
Yes, Cha Jeong-suk speaking.
네, 차정숙님이 말씀하십니다.
Right now?
지금 바로?
The patient's brain MRI came out.
환자의 뇌 MRI가 나왔습니다.
She had a headache for two months, right?
그녀는 두 달 동안 두통을 겪었죠, 그렇죠?
Yes, that's right.
네, 맞습니다.
If you look at the image,
이미지를 보시면,
it's white to the right of the middle cerebral artery.
오른쪽은 흰색이야 중대뇌동맥의.
A cerebral infarction occurred as the blood wasn't able to flow there.
뇌경색이 발생했습니다. 거기에는 피가 흐르지 못했기 때문이다.
If you look at the start of the right internal carotid artery
시작을 보면 오른쪽 내부 경동맥의
and the left vertebral artery, both show signs of stenosis.
그리고 왼쪽 척추동맥, 둘 다 협착의 징후를 보입니다.
But thankfully, fibrinolytic therapy can be done right away.
하지만 다행스럽게도 섬유소용해치료는 바로 할 수 있습니다.
And we want to proceed immediately.
그리고 우리는 즉시 진행하고 싶습니다.
Yes, okay.
응, 알았어.
Doctor.
의사.
You must've been worried.
걱정되셨을 텐데요.
All the blood clots were broken down well.
혈전이 모두 잘 분해되었습니다.
She can get better right away, but it can differ for each case.
그 사람은 당장 좋아질 수도 있고, 하지만 경우마다 다를 수 있습니다.
We'll follow up on her vitals and symptoms in the ICU
우리는 그녀의 활력소에 대한 후속 조치를 취할 것입니다 ICU에서의 증상
and monitor her progress through imaging tests.
그녀의 진행 상황을 모니터링하고 영상검사를 통해
I see.
알겠어요.
Thank you, Professor.
감사합니다, 교수님.
Sure.
확신하는.
Mom.
엄마.
Is it okay?
괜찮나요?
Yes, of course.
물론이죠.
It's okay. You did well.
괜찮아요. 잘했어요.
Okay?
좋아요?
CHOI SEUNG-HI IN OFFICE
최승희 사무실에서
PATIENT NAME: OH DEOK-RYE DIAGNOSIS: RA (RHEUMATOID ARTHRITIS)
환자 이름 : 오덕례 진단: RA(류마티스 관절염)
Ms. Oh Deok-rye received many localized injections in her joints
오덕례씨가 받았습니다. 그녀의 관절에 많은 국소 주사를 맞았습니다.
and was admitted after visiting many departments.
그리고 입학했다 여러 부서를 방문한 후.
But she's very depressed as her pain still hasn't improved.
하지만 그녀는 매우 우울해요 아직까지 통증이 호전되지 않았기 때문입니다.
Dr. Cha must be very worried.
차박사님이 많이 걱정하시겠네요.
What on earth is the issue?
도대체 무엇이 문제인가?
She has pain in both shoulders, her neck, and thighs.
양쪽 어깨에 통증이 있고, 그녀의 목과 허벅지.
She has severe early morning stiffness that makes it hard to move.
그녀는 이른 아침 경직이 심합니다 그래서 움직이기가 힘들어요.
She can't climb stairs either.
그녀는 계단도 오를 수 없습니다.
Over six months, she had six kilograms of weight loss, hot flashes, and asthenia,
6개월에 걸쳐 그녀는 6kg의 체중을 감량했습니다. 체중감소, 안면홍조, 무력증,
so she was diagnosed and treated for rheumatoid arthritis.
그래서 그녀는 진단을 받았어요 그리고 류마티스관절염 치료를 받았습니다.
But there was no improvement.
그러나 개선이 없었습니다.
Are there no issues with her labs and image tests?
연구실에는 문제가 없나요? 그리고 이미지 테스트?
Her ESR and CRP levels have gone up. Her tumor markers are normal.
그녀의 ESR과 CRP 수준이 올라갔습니다. 그녀의 종양 표지자는 정상입니다.
And her ANA, RF, and Anti-CCP are too.
그리고 그녀의 ANA, RF, Anti-CCP도 마찬가지입니다.
Her electromyography and electroneurography tests,
그녀의 근전도검사 그리고 전기신경학 테스트,
and even her WBBS have normal results.
그녀의 WBBS조차도 정상적인 결과를 얻었습니다.
Has she taken fibromyalgia or psychiatric medication?
그녀는 섬유근육통에 걸렸나요? 아니면 정신과 약?
Yes, but there was very little effect.
네, 하지만 효과는 거의 없었습니다.
All her neurological exams show no issue either.
그녀의 모든 신경학적 검사는 문제도 없습니다.
Mom.
엄마.
What are you doing? Why are you packing?
뭐하세요? 왜 짐을 싸나요?
I told you I'm going home.
내가 집에 갈 거라고 말했잖아.
Why should I stay here?
내가 왜 여기에 머물러야 합니까?
You have to be treated!
치료를 받아야합니다!
Who said I wasn't going to be treated?
내가 치료받지 않을 거라고 누가 말했습니까?
There are hospitals everywhere.
병원은 어디에나 있습니다.
How could I get treated by those bastards who hurt my daughter?
내가 어떻게 그 새끼들한테 치료를 받을 수 있겠어? 누가 내 딸을 다치게 했나?
Mom, please. Don't be like this.
엄마, 제발요. 이러지 마세요.
-Please, Mom. -Move.
-제발요, 엄마. -이동하다.
-Mom, don't do this! -Move!
-엄마, 이러지 마세요! -이동하다!
Let go.
가자.
Your daughter is a doctor at this hospital!
당신의 딸은 의사입니다 이 병원에서!
Mom.
엄마.
You can be treated at a different hospital…
치료를 받으실 수 있습니다 다른 병원에서…
but I…
하지만 나는…
I…
나는…
I don't want you to be sick somewhere without me.
나는 당신이 아픈 것을 원하지 않습니다 나 없이 어딘가에.
I don't want to even imagine it!
상상조차 하고 싶지 않아요!
Mom, I can't fix your illness,
엄마, 나는 당신의 병을 고칠 수 없어요
but at the very least, I can be with you here.
하지만 적어도, 나는 여기서 당신과 함께 있을 수 있습니다.
If I'm not with you…
내가 당신과 함께 있지 않다면…
You're just going to say you're okay again!
당신은 단지 말할 것입니다 넌 또 괜찮아!
Stop crying, you're an adult.
그만 울어라 넌 어른이구나
I don't want you to be sick.
나는 당신이 아프기를 원하지 않습니다.
You know I'm not just saying this, right?
내가 이 말만 하는 게 아닌 거 아시죠?
Gusan University Hospital is the best in the country.
구산대학교병원 국내 최고입니다.
Of course I know. After all, my daughter works here.
물론 알아요. 결국 내 딸이 여기서 일해요.
And…
그리고…
And what?
그리고 무엇?
I get an employee discount here.
여기서는 직원 할인을 받습니다.
Jeez!
이런!
Goodness.
선량.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
Mom, you should get treated and get better quickly, okay?
엄마, 치료를 받아야 해요 그리고 빨리 낫자, 알았지?
You know that you're all that I have, right?
당신은 그것을 알고 넌 내가 가진 전부야, 그렇지?
Let's get you better soon, okay?
빨리 낫게 해주세요, 알았죠?
Come in.
들어오세요.
What can I…
나는 무엇을 할 수 있습니까?
Hello.
안녕하세요.
What brings you here?
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
I don't have a lot of time, so maybe next time--
시간이 별로 없어요. 그럼 아마도 다음번에는--
I'm sorry.
미안해요.
For what?
무엇을 위해?
For causing Eun-seo's arm injury.
은서에게 팔 부상을 입힌 죄.
I heard she can't go to the art school she wants to this year.
그 사람 미술학원에 갈 수 없다고 들었어 그녀는 올해를 원해요.
You should apologize to Eun-seo.
은서한테 사과해야지.
I'll apologize to her too.
나도 그 사람한테 사과할게.
I will.
그럴게요.
But I came here to ask a favor.
그런데 부탁 하나를 하려고 여기까지 왔습니다.
-A favor? -Please break up with my father.
- 부탁이요? - 아버지와 헤어지세요.
I know you came first before my mom.
엄마보다 네가 먼저 온 줄 알아.
Eun-seo told me everything.
은서씨가 다 말해줬어요.
And asked me to give my dad to her.
그리고 아빠에게 선물을 달라고 하더군요.
My dad
우리 아빠
may not be a perfect father.
완벽한 아버지는 아닐 수도 있다.
But still, I'm scared of losing him entirely.
하지만 여전히, 나는 그를 완전히 잃을 까봐 두렵습니다.
I'm not expecting this favor for free.
나는 이 호의를 공짜로 바라는 것이 아니다.
I'll receive punishment too.
나도 벌을 받겠다.
I'll give up
나는 포기할 것이다
on art school…
미술학교에서…
just like Eun-seo.
은서처럼.
And…
그리고…
please save my grandmother too.
우리 할머니도 살려주세요.
I-rang.
아이링.
Your hair has grown so much.
머리가 너무 많이 자랐어요.
You look like a grown woman.
당신은 어른처럼 보입니다.
Grandma, I'm all grown up now.
할머니, 저는 이제 다 컸어요.
Jeez, as if.
이런, 마치.
You're still a baby in my eyes.
내 눈에는 넌 아직 아기야.
-Come here. -I said I'm all grown up.
-이리 오세요. - 다 컸다고 했어요.
I-rang.
아이링.
When you were four or five,
네가 네 살인가 다섯 살이었을 때,
I would pick you up from daycare, and you would come running to me.
내가 너를 어린이집에서 데리러 갈 텐데, 그리고 당신은 나에게 달려올 것입니다.
You would scream "Grandma!" and plop into my arms.
당신은 "할머니!"라고 소리칠 것이다. 그리고 내 품에 안겨요.
Goodness.
선량.
You were so pretty then, I thought my heart would burst.
그땐 정말 예뻤는데, 심장이 터질 것 같았어요.
Even now, my heart feels soft and fuzzy
지금도 내 마음은 포근하고 몽롱한 느낌이에요
whenever I think of that moment.
그 순간이 생각날 때마다.
I-rang.
아이링.
I wasn't able to raise your mother
난 네 엄마를 키울 수 없었어
with the same care and love as you received.
같은 배려로 그리고 받은 대로 사랑하세요.
So make sure you give your mom all the love you can.
그러니 꼭 엄마한테 드리세요 당신이 할 수 있는 모든 사랑.
Okay, I will.
알았어, 그럴게.
Gosh.
이런.
Are you being cute only to Grandma again?
또 할머니한테만 귀엽게 굴어?
Grandma's sick. Hurry up and get down from there.
할머니가 아프세요. 서둘러서 거기에서 내려오세요.
Mom, Grandma said I was prettier than you.
엄마, 할머니는 내가 당신보다 예쁘다고 했어요.
-Mom, did you really say that? -Jeez, pay no attention to it.
-엄마, 정말 그렇게 말했어요? - 이런, 신경 쓰지 마세요.
How could you say that? Your daughter should be prettier.
어떻게 그런 말을 할 수 있니? 딸이 더 예뻐야 해요.
Look.
바라보다.
You're scaring me.
당신은 나를 겁주고 있어요.
Aren't you hungry? Do you want to eat something?
배고프지 않나요? 뭔가 먹고 싶니?
Do you have time right now?
지금 시간이 있나요?
It's so comfortable to move around sitting like this.
돌아다니기 너무 편해요 이렇게 앉아 있어요.
You should get better soon and walk.
빨리 나아서 걸어가야 할 것 같아요.
I don't like pushing you around in a wheelchair.
난 너를 밀어붙이는 게 싫어 휠체어에.
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
Yes?
예?
The stars are so pretty.
별이 너무 예뻐요.
They really are.
정말 그렇습니다.
Don't consider your life to be too miserable.
당신의 인생을 고려하지 마십시오 너무 비참해지려고.
Life can't only be filled with good things.
인생은 채울 수만은 없어 좋은 것들로.
You have Jung-min and I-rang.
정민이와 아이랑이 있어요.
And after going in circles, you became a doctor again.
그리고 원을 그리며 들어간 후, 당신은 다시 의사가 되었습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
If I died now, I wouldn't be too sad about it
만약 내가 지금 죽는다면, 나는 그것에 대해 너무 슬퍼하지 않을 것입니다
I'll be going after seeing so many good things.
나는 갈 것이다 좋은 걸 많이 본 후에.
I mean it.
진심이에요.
What?
무엇?
Did we turn off the lights?
우리가 불을 껐나요?
Did we?
우리는 그랬나요?
-Ta-da. -Grandma.
-짜-다. -할머니.
You startled me.
당신은 나를 놀라게 했습니다.
What is this? It's not even my birthday.
이게 뭔가요? 내 생일도 아닌데.
Are parties only for birthdays?
파티는 생일에만 가능한가요?
We prepared this so you can smile.
여러분이 웃으실 수 있도록 준비했습니다.
Ta-da! There are presents too.
짜잔! 선물도 있어요.
My goodness.
이럴 수가.
These are all so expensive.
이것들은 모두 너무 비쌉니다.
Where did you kids get the money for this?
너희 꼬마들은 이걸 살 돈을 어디서 났니?
I saved up my allowance.
용돈을 모았습니다.
When I would play house with you when I was young,
너랑 집에서 놀 때 내가 어렸을 때,
I remember you saying you wanted a trench coat
나는 당신이 말한 것을 기억합니다 넌 트렌치코트를 원했지
and a pretty handbag like the one Audrey Hepburn wore.
그리고 예쁜 핸드백 오드리 햅번이 입었던 옷처럼요.
Jung-min bought the handbag.
정민이가 핸드백을 샀어요.
We played house before you went to elementary school.
우리는 집에서 놀았어요 초등학교 들어가기 전에.
You remembered that?
그거 기억나?
Gosh.
이런.
Who do you two take after to be this smart?
너희 둘은 누구를 닮는가? 이렇게 똑똑해지려고?
What do you mean by who?
누구라는 말은 무슨 뜻인가요?
They take after their mother.
그들은 어머니를 닮습니다.
Grandma, the candles.
할머니, 촛불.
You must be so happy, Mom.
정말 행복하겠어요, 엄마.
OH DEOK-RYE
오덕례
It's so pretty.
너무 예뻐요.
Mom, look.
엄마, 보세요.
I picked them out.
나는 그들을 골랐다.
MY DAUGHTER EUN-SEO MOM, WHEN ARE YOU COMING HOME?
내 딸 은서 엄마, 집에는 언제 오시나요?
I HAVE A LOT OF MATERIALS TO LOOK OVER SO I'LL BE LATE
살펴봐야 할 자료가 너무 많아요 그래서 늦을 것 같아요
DON'T WAIT FOR ME AND GO TO BED
나를 기다리지 말고 자러 가세요
I LOVE YOU, MY DAUGHTER
사랑해요, 내 딸
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
Ma'am.
부인.
Gosh.
이런.
You must be busy. Why did you come all the way here?
바쁘시겠어요. 왜 여기까지 왔나요?
Ma'am.
부인.
Please don't say that. Of course I should come.
그런 말은 하지 마세요. 물론 나도 와야지.
It's tough, isn't it?
힘든 일이지, 그렇지?
No, it's fine.
아니요, 괜찮아요.
You didn't have to buy all this.
이 모든 것을 구입할 필요는 없었습니다.
Your mom looks so gaunt.
네 엄마가 정말 수척해 보이시구나.
No diagnosis yet?
아직 진단이 없나요?
They're doing various tests.
다양한 테스트를 진행하고 있습니다.
I'm looking into it too.
저도 알아보고 있어요.
But it's not easy.
하지만 쉽지 않습니다.
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
My brother's friend is a professor
내 동생 친구가 교수인데
in the Neurology Department at Aseong Hospital.
신경과에서 아성병원에서.
How about you take your mother there?
엄마를 거기로 모셔가는 게 어때?
Aseong Hospital?
아성병원?
How is their Neurology Department?
신경과는 어떤가요?
What's there to say? It's the best in the country.
무슨 말을 해야 할까요? 국내 최고입니다.
I know you want to keep your mom by your side,
네가 엄마를 지키고 싶어하는 거 알아 당신 곁에서,
but her treatment takes the top priority.
하지만 그녀의 치료가 최우선입니다.
Think about it if there's no progress here.
생각해 보세요 여기에 진전이 없다면.
I'll ask that professor to pay special attention to your mother.
그 교수님한테 물어볼게 어머니에게 특별한 관심을 기울이십시오.
Yes, Chief.
네, 국장님.
Ms. Oh Deok-rye?
오덕례 선생님?
I'll go over right away.
바로 가보겠습니다.
Dr. Cha.
차 박사.
I have to tell you something about your mother.
당신에게 말해야 할 게 있어요 네 어머니에 대해서.
You can tell me here.
여기서 말씀하시면 됩니다.
I did a biopsy after discussing Ms. Oh's condition
생체검사를 했어요 오씨의 상태를 논의한 후
with professors in the Rheumatology and Neurosurgery Departments.
류마티스내과 교수들과 함께 및 신경외과.
Based on the biopsy of her temporal artery,
생체검사를 토대로 그녀의 측두동맥,
there was large cell infiltration and intimal hyperplasia.
큰 세포 침윤이 있었습니다 및 내막 증식.
It's giant cell arteritis.
거대세포동맥염입니다.
Your mother has no risk factors,
어머니는 위험인자가 없으시며,
but the GCA caused her cerebral infarction.
하지만 GCA로 인해 그녀의 뇌경색.
My diagnosis is that your mother is suffering from polymyalgia rheumatica.
내 진단은 당신의 어머니가 류마티스성 다발근통을 앓고 있습니다.
I heard she's moving hospitals.
그녀가 병원을 옮기고 있다고 들었어.
Even if she does, have prednisone administered to her first.
그녀가 그렇다고 해도, 그녀에게 먼저 프레드니손을 투여했습니다.
Even better, have her treated here.
더 좋은 점은 여기에서 치료를 받는 것입니다.
Not only is she your mother,
그녀는 당신의 어머니일 뿐만 아니라,
but also she's my patient.
하지만 그 사람도 내 환자야.
Also,
또한,
take care of your own health too.
자신의 건강도 잘 챙기세요.
You don't look well.
당신은 표정이 좋지 않습니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Gosh, Dr. Cha. You're here too.
이런, 차 박사님. 당신도 여기에 있습니다.
Ms. Oh Deok-rye, how are you feeling today?
오덕례 선생님, 오늘 기분이 어때?
I feel so much better than before.
이전보다 훨씬 나아진 것 같아요.
My shoulder barely hurts,
어깨가 거의 안 아프고,
and I have enough strength in my legs to go on walks.
그리고 다리에 힘이 충분해요 산책하러.
Thank you so much, Professor.
정말 감사합니다, 교수님.
It's Professor Choi here who you should be thanking.
여기 최교수님이세요 당신이 감사해야 할 사람.
Professor Choi worked hard on this.
최 교수는 이를 위해 애썼다.
We'll monitor you for a few days.
며칠 동안 모니터링하겠습니다.
You can be discharged afterward.
이후 퇴원하실 수 있습니다.
-Okay. -Thank you for being so considerate.
-좋아요. - 이렇게 배려해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Dr. Cha, you have gone through a lot.
차 박사님, 수고가 많으셨습니다.
You can relax now.
이제 긴장을 풀 수 있습니다.
Goodbye, ma'am.
안녕히 계세요, 부인.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Thank you…
감사합니다…
for treating my mother.
어머니를 치료하기 위해.
But that doesn't mean I forgive you.
하지만 그렇다고 해서 내가 당신을 용서한다는 뜻은 아닙니다.
No.
아니요.
I can't forgive you.
나는 당신을 용서할 수 없습니다.
But still, I'm grateful for what you did.
하지만 그래도 당신이 한 일에 감사드립니다.
I thought I should say thank you.
고맙다고 해야겠다고 생각했어요.
I-rang came to see me.
아이랑이 나를 만나러 왔어요.
She said she was sorry she injured Eun-seo.
그녀는 미안하다고 말했다 그녀는 은서에게 상처를 입혔다.
And she said she'd give up on art school this year too.
그리고 그녀는 포기하겠다고 하더군요 올해도 미술학교에 가요.
Tell her to go to the school she wants.
그녀가 원하는 학교에 가라고 말하세요.
And she doesn't have to feel guilty about Eun-seo anymore.
그리고 그녀는 죄책감을 느낄 필요가 없어요 더 이상 은서에 대해서.
We…
우리는…
hurt our kids too much.
우리 아이들에게 너무 큰 상처를 줬어요.
Something feels ominous.
뭔가 불길한 느낌이 듭니다.
DIVORCE APPLICATION (APPOINTMENT OF PARENTAL RIGHTS)
이혼 신청 (친권의 지정)
SEO IN-HO, CHA JEONG-SUK
서인호, 차정석
What is this?
이것은 무엇입니까?
Isn't it obvious?
분명하지 않나요?
It's a divorce application.
이혼신청서 입니다.
Having it by mutual agreement is better than going to trial, right?
상호 합의에 의해 갖는 것 재판에 가는 것보다는 낫겠죠?
I'll text you the necessary paperwork, so let me know when you're ready.
필요한 서류는 문자로 보내드릴게요 그러니 준비되면 알려주세요.
I can go by myself to turn in the papers.
나 혼자 가서 서류를 제출할 수 있어요.
How can you just act as you please?
어떻게 마음대로 행동할 수 있나요?
A divorce can't be done alone.
이혼은 혼자 할 수 없습니다.
I won't cooperate if you'll do things however you want!
나는 협력하지 않을 것이다 당신이 원하는대로 일을 할 거라면!
I mean,
내 말은,
do you really have to do this when your mother is still recovering?
정말 이걸 꼭 해야 해? 네 엄마가 아직 회복 중이실 때야?
Yes, I need to do this.
예, 이 일을 해야 합니다.
This divorce has become more urgent and important to me than anything else.
이 이혼이 더 시급해졌어 그리고 그 무엇보다 나에게 중요해요.
My daughter.
내 딸.
Your daughters are suffering.
당신의 딸들이 고통 받고 있습니다.
The kids are in pain because of us.
우리 때문에 아이들이 고통받고 있어요.
My mother is recovering,
어머니는 회복 중이시고,
and I don't want to use anything else as an excuse to delay this.
그리고 나는 다른 것을 사용하고 싶지 않아요 이것을 지연시키기 위한 핑계로.
I want to end things quickly.
빨리 일을 끝내고 싶어요.
I refuse to get divorced!
나는 이혼을 거부합니다!
So if you want a divorce,
그러니까 이혼하고 싶으면
you can take this to court.
이 문제를 법원에 가져갈 수 있습니다.
I'm appalled at your audacity.
나는 당신의 대담함에 놀랐습니다.
You're the spouse at fault! You're the one who's causing the divorce!
당신은 배우자의 잘못입니다! 이혼을 초래한 건 바로 당신이에요!
That's why I got down on my knees and apologized!
그래서 나는 무릎을 꿇었습니다. 그리고 사과했다!
And I'm trying my best to please you!
그리고 나는 당신을 기쁘게하기 위해 최선을 다하고 있습니다!
If you take this to court…
이걸 법정에 가져가면...
I'm going to stop the divorce,
이혼을 막겠다.
even if I have to spend my entire fortune.
전재산을 다 써버려도.
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
We used to come here to avoid meeting our co-workers.
우리는 여기에 오곤 했어요 동료를 만나지 않으려고.
I know.
알아요.
You said you'd do everything you can for your wife,
당신은 모든 것을 다 하겠다고 말했어요 당신은 당신의 아내를 위해 할 수 있습니다
so why did you come to a place we often went together?
그럼 넌 왜 그런 곳에 왔니? 우리 자주 같이 갔지?
I just came.
방금 왔어요.
What do you expect me to do when my legs just brought me here?
내가 무엇을 하기를 기대하는가? 내 다리가 나를 여기로 데려왔을 때?
I mean,
내 말은,
what is going on?
무슨 일이야?
You're treating me to drinks at a place like this?
당신은 나에게 술을 대접하고 있어요 이런 곳에?
Jeez, do you have to pay all the time?
이런, 항상 비용을 지불해야 하나요?
I wanted to treat you once too.
나도 한 번 치료를 받고 싶었어요.
Cheers.
건배.
Jeez, I guess you're feeling relaxed now that your mother is recovering.
이런, 너 좀 편안해진 것 같구나 이제 네 엄마가 회복 중이니까.
Maybe it's because of that, but I feel like I'm in a hurry.
어쩌면 그것 때문일지도 모르지만, 하지만 너무 서두르는 것 같아요.
What?
무엇?
I told In-ho that I want a divorce.
나는 인호에게 이혼하고 싶다고 말했다.
Really?
정말?
I gave him the papers.
나는 그에게 서류를 주었다.
What did he say?
그가 뭐라고 말했습니까?
He doesn't want a divorce
그 사람은 이혼을 원하지 않아요
and told me to go to court.
그리고 법정에 가보라고 하더군요.
Is he crazy?
그 사람 미쳤나요?
I'm sorry!
죄송합니다!
Seung-hi, I'm really sorry. I deserve to die.
승희야, 정말 미안해. 나는 죽을 자격이 있습니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
Please be quiet.
조용히 해주세요.
My life has been…
내 인생은…
like a shirt that I buttoned up wrong from the very start.
단추를 잘못 채운 셔츠처럼 처음부터.
These buttons.
이 버튼.
They were fastened onto you,
그들은 당신에게 고정되었습니다.
but I mistakenly fastened them onto Jeong-suk.
하지만 내가 실수로 정숙에게 묶어주었다.
I tried to unbutton and button them again. And then I kept trying.
나는 단추를 풀고 다시 단추를 눌러 보았습니다. 그리고 계속해서 노력했어요.
But in the end,
그러나 결국,
all the buttons fell off.
버튼이 다 떨어졌어요.
This is all my fault though, right?
그래도 이게 다 내 잘못이겠죠?
At least you know that.
적어도 당신은 그것을 알고 있습니다.
But now she's asking for a divorce?
그런데 지금 그 사람이 이혼을 요구하고 있는 걸까요?
A divorce!
이혼!
How could she do that to me?
그녀가 어떻게 나에게 그런 짓을 할 수 있니?
I didn't do everything right.
나는 모든 일을 제대로 하지 않았습니다.
But…
하지만…
I even got on my knees
무릎을 꿇기도 했어
and begged her to forgive me.
그리고 그녀에게 나를 용서해달라고 간청했습니다.
You got on your knees?
무릎을 꿇었나요?
Yes!
예!
Why are you telling me this?
왜 나한테 이런 말을 하는 거야?
Drink slowly.
천천히 마셔보세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
It's fine to start a new life.
새로운 삶을 시작하는 것이 좋습니다.
There are plenty of better fish in the sea.
더 좋은 생선이 많아요 바다에서.
Once you let go of Seo In-ho, you can reel in Roy Kim.
일단 서인호를 놓으면 로이킴을 릴 수 있습니다.
What kind of nonsense are you saying?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하고 있습니까?
What do you mean by nonsense?
넌센스란 무슨 뜻인가요?
I have reasonable suspicion.
나는 합리적인 의심을 가지고 있습니다.
Hey, in what way or form is that reasonable?
야, 어떤 방식으로든, 어떤 형태로든 그게 합리적인가요?
Did he confess that he liked me or something?
그 사람이 고백했나요? 그 사람이 나를 좋아했다고?
Jeez.
이런.
Okay, now it's your turn to talk.
자, 이제 당신이 말할 차례입니다.
About Jeong-suk.
정숙에 대해서.
I…
나는…
No.
아니요.
Not really.
그렇지 않습니다.
Well.
잘.
He didn't say that.
그는 그렇게 말하지 않았습니다.
But do you really have no feelings for him?
그런데 정말 있나요? 그 사람에 대한 감정은 없나요?
Hey.
여기요.
I don't have the energy to think about that right now.
에너지가 없어 지금 당장 그것에 대해 생각해보세요.
My mother is sick.
우리 어머니는 아프다.
I'm about to get a divorce.
나는 곧 이혼할 예정이다.
My daughter is in 12th grade. I'm working.
제 딸은 12학년이에요. 나는 일하고 있습니다.
My mind is all over the place.
내 마음은 온통 흩어졌습니다.
But if you get a divorce, will you really be okay
하지만 이혼을 하면 너 정말 괜찮을까?
seeing Seo In-ho and Choi Seung-hi live a good life together?
서인호, 최승희를 만나다 같이 잘 살아?
Can the two of them…
과연 두 사람은…
really live a good life together?
정말 같이 잘 살아?
If I were Seung-hi,
내가 승희라면,
I think I'd finally see things for what they really are.
드디어 뭔가를 보게 될 것 같아 그들이 실제로 무엇인지.
Say there is a limited edition handbag you really want
한정판 핸드백이 있다고 해 당신은 정말로 원해요
and you're really anxious about it selling out.
그리고 당신은 정말 매진될까봐 불안하다.
But once you actually get your hands on it,
하지만 일단 실제로 손을 들어보세요.
that feeling of happiness doesn't last long.
그 행복감 오래 가지 않습니다.
You just put it away in your closet and forget about it.
그냥 옷장에 넣어두시면 됩니다 그리고 잊어버리세요.
That's true.
그것은 사실이다.
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
Hey, a handbag isn't the same thing as a man.
야, 핸드백은 아니야 남자와 똑같은 것.
It's different.
그것은 다릅니다.
A handbag is better.
핸드백이 더 좋습니다.
Cheers.
건배.
Pull yourself together.
함께 힘을 모아보세요.
Get up.
일어나세요.
Get up!
일어나세요!
I said get up!
내가 일어나라고 했어!
I can't believe this.
나는 이것을 믿을 수 없다.
Come on, one, two.
자, 하나, 둘.
-Did you call a designated driver? -I called one earlier.
- 대리운전자를 부르셨나요? - 아까 전화했어요.
Go first.
먼저 가세요.
I'll walk a bit and take a taxi.
조금 걸어가다가 택시를 탈게요.
Okay.
좋아요.
-Get home safe. -Okay.
- 집에 안전하게 도착하세요. -좋아요.
Jeong-suk.
정숙.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Go.
가다.
-Bye.
-안녕.
-Don't trip and fall. -I get it.
- 넘어지거나 넘어지지 마세요. - 알겠습니다.
-Get home safely. -I told you, I get it!
- 집에 무사히 도착하세요. -말했잖아, 알겠어!
It's nice that you two have a place to go even if you go your separate ways.
너희 둘이 갈 곳이 있어서 다행이야 각자의 길을 가더라도.
Seo In-ho can go to Choi Seung-hi.
서인호는 최승희에게 갈 수 있다.
And Cha Jeong-suk can go to Roy.
그리고 차정숙은 로이에게 갈 수 있다.
No.
아니요.
Not really.
그렇지 않습니다.
Really?
정말?
I know that my feelings right now
지금 내 감정을 알아
could cause trouble for Dr. Cha.
차 박사에게 문제를 일으킬 수 있습니다.
So right now…
그래서 지금 당장…
it's a no.
그것은 아니오입니다.
Let's just say I feigned ignorance and said, "No."
내가 무지한 척했다고 가정해보자. "아니요."
That's scarier than saying you like her.
그 사람을 좋아한다고 말하는 것보다 그게 더 무섭다.
I'm lonely.
나는 외롭다.
So lonely.
너무 외로워요.
I need another drink.
한 잔 더 마셔야 해요.
PROFESSOR PARK HO-WON
박호원 교수
Your call cannot be connected. Redirecting to voicemail…
통화를 연결할 수 없습니다. 음성 메일로 리디렉션 중…
Did he take my money and go off the grid?
그 사람이 내 돈을 가져가고 그리드에서 나갔나요?
It's unfair that I'm being labeled an adulteress.
그건 불공평해요 나는 간음한 여자로 분류되고 있습니다.
Now my money's gone too.
이제 내 돈도 없어졌습니다.
Wait, do I have to report this to the police?
잠깐만요, 이거 신고해야 하나요? 경찰에게?
Mother, you're up early.
어머니, 일찍 일어나셨어요.
Why did you stay out without calling?
왜 전화도 없이 밖에 있었나요?
Were you in surgery all night?
밤새 수술했어요?
Yes, I had a difficult patient.
네, 어려운 환자가 있었습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
This came from the court. What is it?
이것은 법원에서 나온 것입니다. 그것은 무엇입니까?
The court?
법원?
SEOUL FAMILY COURT TO SEO IN-HO
서울가정법원 서인호에게
DIVORCE PETITION
이혼 청원서
Oh, my. Is this a divorce petition?
아, 이런. 이혼소송인가요?
For crying out loud!
큰 소리로 울었기 때문에!
Are you two really getting divorced?
둘이 정말 이혼하는 건가요?
What have you been doing this whole time? You should have won her back by now!
그동안 뭐하고 있었나요? 지금쯤이면 당신이 그녀를 되찾았어야 했어요!
You'll be the death of me.
당신은 나의 죽음이 될 것입니다.
So this is how our family gets destroyed.
그래서 우리 가족이 망하는 거죠.
What on earth is this? What is the meaning of this?
도대체 이게 뭐죠? 이것의 의미는 무엇입니까?
You know what it is.
당신은 그것이 무엇인지 알고 있습니다.
How could you send me a divorce petition
어떻게 나에게 이혼 청원서를 보낼 수 있니?
after asking me to divorce by mutual agreement?
나한테 물어본 후 서로 합의해서 이혼하나요?
Are you really going to end things with me?
정말 가시나요? 나랑 끝내려고?
Do you want it so badly?
그렇게까지 원하시나요?
I wanted to end things quietly with a divorce by mutual agreement.
조용히 끝내고 싶었는데 서로 합의에 의한 이혼으로.
But you refused.
하지만 당신은 거절했어요.
You told me to go to court.
법원에 가라고 하더군요.
I expected that, so I prepared in advance.
그럴 거라고 예상해서 미리 준비했어요.
Did you think I really meant that? I said it because I didn't want a divorce!
내가 정말 그런 말을 했다고 생각했나요? 이혼하고 싶지 않아서 그런 말을 한 거야!
Seriously, do you not know how to read between the lines?
진심으로 모르시나요? 줄 사이를 읽는 방법은 무엇입니까?
I'm trying to tell you that I'm determined to get this divorce.
나는 당신에게 그것을 말하려고 노력하고 있습니다 나는 이번 이혼을 하기로 결심했습니다.
What's the real reason…
진짜 이유는 무엇인가…
you want to get divorced this badly?
이렇게까지 이혼하고 싶니?
What does that mean?
그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
Is it because of that punk?
그 새끼 때문인가?
Roy Kimberley?
로이 킴벌리?
Don't get ahead of yourself.
자신보다 앞서 나가지 마십시오.
Do you think that decent young man is into you?
당신은 생각합니까? 그 괜찮은 청년이 당신을 좋아해요?
My gosh.
맙소사.
Jeez.
이런.
You're the most pathetic loser I've ever seen.
넌 가장 불쌍한 패배자야 본 적 있어요.
Thank you so much for helping me
도와주셔서 정말 감사해요
get rid of the little affection I had left for you.
작은 애정을 없애라 나는 당신을 위해 떠났습니다.
Jeez.
이런.
You can't just leave like this.
이대로 떠날 수는 없습니다.
We're not done talking!
아직 얘기가 끝나지 않았습니다!
Ms. Park, can I please have Shin Gyu-seon's chart?
박 선생님, 좀 드실 수 있나요? 신규선의 차트?
One moment.
잠시만요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Hello? This is the Seocho Police Station's Women's and Juvenile Affairs Division.
안녕하세요? 서초경찰서 입니다 여성청소년과
Is this Roy Kimberley?
이 사람이 로이 킴벌리인가요?
I called to give you good news.
좋은 소식을 전하려고 전화했어요.
Good news?
좋은 소식이요?
Dr. Cha!
차 박사님!
Did something good happen?
좋은 일 있었나요?
Yes.
예.
And I wanted to tell you first.
그리고 먼저 말씀드리고 싶었어요.
Really?
정말?
You really found your family?
정말로 가족을 찾았나요?
I can't believe this.
나는 이것을 믿을 수 없다.
So are you going to meet your family?
그럼 가족을 만나러 가시나요?
Yes.
예.
They say I have an older brother and older sisters.
나한테 형이 있다고 하던데 그리고 언니들.
I see.
알겠어요.
They raised them, so I wonder why they put me up for adoption.
그 사람들이 키웠는데 왜 그런 건지 궁금해요 그들은 나를 입양 보내주었습니다.
I heard that families with financial difficulties back then
가족들이라고 들었는데 당시 경제적 어려움으로
would sometimes put their youngest up for adoption.
가끔은 막내를 입양시키세요.
That way, they would go to college in a good environment.
그렇게 하면 그들은 대학에 갈 것이다. 좋은 환경에서.
What's the point of a good environment if there are no parents?
좋은 환경이 무슨 소용이 있나요? 부모가 없다면?
And I don't understand the point of college either.
그리고 난 이해가 안 돼요 대학의 요점.
But I still want to meet them.
하지만 나는 아직도 그들을 만나고 싶다.
-I'm curious. -Yes, you should meet them.
- 궁금해요. - 응, 만나봐야 해.
But…
하지만…
don't have high expectations.
큰 기대는 하지 마세요.
No expectations. I'll keep that in mind.
기대가 없습니다. 그 점을 명심하겠습니다.
But, Dr. Cha,
그런데 차 박사님,
I have a favor to ask.
부탁드릴 게 있어요.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
When I go to meet my family,
가족을 만나러 갈 때,
can you come with me?
나와 함께 갈 수 있나요?
I know you're having a hard time lately, but please come with me.
요즘 힘든 시간을 보내고 있다는 걸 알아요. 하지만 나와 함께 가주세요.
I'm really nervous,
정말 긴장돼요
to be honest.
솔직히 말하면.
Excuse me. How do I apply for a leave of absence?
실례합니다. 휴학은 어떻게 신청하나요?
Is something wrong?
뭔가 문제가 있나요?
I'm planning to enlist, so I just want to look into it first.
입대할 예정인데, 그래서 먼저 알아보고 싶습니다.
You'll have a hard time if you enlist now.
지금 입대하면 힘들 것 같아요.
You should finish your residency first.
먼저 레지던트를 끝내야 합니다.
What did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
Say it again slowly.
천천히 다시 말해 보세요.
I'm going to the military.
나는 군대에 갈 것이다.
I won't ask you to wait for me.
나는 당신에게 나를 기다려달라고 요청하지 않을 것입니다.
I thought you were going after your residency.
난 당신이 갈 줄 알았는데 레지던트 이후.
I need some time to think.
생각할 시간이 좀 필요해요.
It's not just because of Ms. Yoo Ji-seon's incident.
뿐만 아니라 유지선 씨 사건 때문이다.
I want to find a specialty that fits me.
나에게 맞는 전공을 찾고 싶다.
I just came to the Surgery Department because of my father.
방금 외과에 왔어요 아버지 때문에.
Sure.
확신하는.
That's your decision, so that's fine by me.
그건 당신의 결정이에요. 그래서 저는 괜찮습니다.
But are you breaking up with me?
그런데 나랑 헤어지는 거야?
I never said that.
나는 그런 말을 한 적이 없습니다.
I'm just saying you don't have to wait for me.
난 그냥 말하는거야 나를 기다릴 필요는 없습니다.
Hey, be more honest.
야, 좀 더 솔직해지자.
Would you be happy if I date some other guy?
당신은 행복할까요? 내가 다른 남자랑 사귀면?
Of course I'd hate it.
물론 나는 그것을 싫어할 것이다.
Then tell me to wait for you!
그럼 기다리라고 말해!
Make it clear.
명확하게 하세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Then wait for me.
그럼 나를 기다려주세요.
You better not date some other guy.
다른 남자와 데이트하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
They're all staring.
그들은 모두 쳐다보고 있어요.
This is crazy.
이건 미친 짓이야.
-You can do it exactly like this. -Yes, okay.
- 이렇게 하면 됩니다. - 응, 알았어.
Dr. Cha, your mother is being discharged today, right?
차 박사님, 당신의 어머니 오늘 퇴원하는 거 맞지?
Yes.
예.
Thank you so much for taking care of my mother this whole time.
배려해주셔서 정말 감사드립니다 내내 우리 엄마한테.
Gosh, it was nothing.
맙소사, 아무것도 아니었어.
We're glad that she's going home healthy.
그녀가 건강하게 집에 돌아가서 다행입니다.
-Aren't you going to her room? -I was going to go now.
- 그 사람 방에 안 가? - 지금 가려고 했어요.
-Have a good day. -You too.
-좋은 하루 보내세요. -너도.
Mom.
엄마.
MY DAUGHTER
내 딸
Thanks to you, I'm being discharged.
덕분에 제가 퇴원하게 되었습니다.
Yes.
예.
Thank you for making me better when no one else could.
나를 더 좋게 만들어줘서 고마워요 다른 누구도 할 수 없을 때.
I thought I was going to wither away and die like this.
시들어버릴 줄 알았는데 그리고 이렇게 죽습니다.
But it feels like I'm finally living again.
하지만 그런 느낌이야 드디어 다시 살게 됐네요.
I came to give you this before I leave.
내가 떠나기 전에 이것을 당신에게 주려고 왔습니다.
It's not filled with money,
돈이 꽉 차 있지도 않고,
so don't get your hopes up.
그러니 희망을 갖지 마세요.
TO DOCTOR CHOI SEUNG-HI…
최승희 박사님께…
When I looked at you, for a moment,
너를 잠시 바라보던 중,
I felt sympathy and affection for you like a daughter.
당신에 대한 동정심과 애정을 느꼈습니다 딸같아.
Though I can no longer look at you with affection,
더 이상 당신을 바라볼 수는 없지만 애정을 담아
I still feel that sympathy.
나는 아직도 그 동정심을 느낀다.
The way I see the world has changed a bit
세상을 보는 눈이 조금 달라졌어
after suffering from a serious illness.
심각한 질병을 앓은 후.
Before, my daily life seemed like nothing,
예전엔 일상이 별것 아닌 것 같았는데
but now, it feels so dear and precious.
그런데 지금은 그게 너무 소중하고 소중한 것 같아요.
Mom, do you want some water?
엄마, 물 좀 드릴까요?
So I want to live whatever life I have left as a kinder person.
그래서 어떤 삶이든 살고 싶어요 나는 더 친절한 사람으로 떠났습니다.
It may be late, but that's what I've decided to do.
늦을 수도 있지만, 하지만 저는 그렇게 하기로 결정했습니다.
I'm saying this to you as a fellow woman and mother.
나는 당신에게 이것을 말하고 있습니다 동료 여성이자 어머니로서.
Do not abandon your chance to become a good person and mother.
기회를 포기하지 마십시오 좋은 사람, 좋은 엄마가 되기 위해.
From now on, live an honorable life for yourself.
이제부터 스스로 명예로운 삶을 살아보세요.
That is when you'll find real happiness.
그때 진정한 행복을 찾게 될 것입니다.
Are you very nervous?
많이 긴장됐나요?
I am.
그래요.
Thank you
감사합니다
for coming with me today.
오늘 나와 함께 가줘서.
Let's say I was building rapport.
내가 관계를 구축하고 있다고 가정 해 봅시다.
You can come in now. Your family is waiting.
지금 들어오시면 됩니다. 당신의 가족이 기다리고 있습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
I hope you have a good time with them.
나는 당신이 그들과 함께 즐거운 시간을 보내길 바랍니다.
I'll be waiting here.
나는 여기서 기다리고 있을게요.
-Okay. -Good luck.
-좋아요. -행운을 빌어요.
I'm nervous.
긴장돼요.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
-My name is Roy. -It's nice to meet you.
-제 이름은 로이예요. -만나서 반가워요.
Please have a seat.
자리에 앉으세요.
This is our father.
이 분은 우리 아버지이십니다.
This is my younger sister, and over there is my younger brother.
이 사람은 내 여동생이에요. 그리고 저기에는 내 남동생이 있어요.
Nice to meet you all.
모두 만나서 반가워요.
You grew up well.
당신은 잘 자랐습니다.
You grew up to be a good man.
당신은 좋은 사람으로 자랐습니다.
I hear you're a doctor.
당신이 의사라고 들었습니다.
Yes.
예.
The only good thing that woman did
그 여자가 유일하게 잘한 일은
was to die early.
일찍 죽을 뻔했다.
If you were raised by your mother, you would've ended up dirt poor.
어머니 밑에서 자랐다면, 당신은 결국 가난하게 끝났을 것입니다.
Father.
아버지.
Why would you say that here?
왜 여기서 그런 말을 합니까?
I'll be straightforward.
나는 간단하게 말할 것이다.
Since you're a doctor, you'll find it easy to understand.
당신은 의사이기 때문에, 이해하기 쉬우실 겁니다.
The reason we found you was because of our father.
우리가 당신을 찾은 이유 우리 아버지 때문이었어.
Our father has acute leukemia.
우리 아버지는 급성 백혈병을 앓고 계십니다.
So…
그래서…
we need someone who can do a bone marrow transplant.
우리에겐 누군가가 필요해 골수 이식을 할 수 있는 사람.
Did you have a good meeting?
좋은 만남 되셨나요?
Yes.
예.
I wanted to meet my mother…
엄마를 만나고 싶었는데...
but she had already passed away.
하지만 그녀는 이미 세상을 떠났습니다.
I see.
알겠어요.
How were your other family members?
다른 가족들은 어땠나요?
Did they look a lot like you?
그 사람들이 당신과 많이 닮았나요?
-Are you going straight to the hospital? -I should.
- 바로 병원으로 가시나요? -해야죠.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
Yes, me too.
응, 나도 마찬가지야.
Then should we grab a taxi?
그럼 택시를 잡아야 할까요?
Okay.
좋아요.
Professor Kim.
김 교수님.
Do you want to run to the hospital?
병원으로 달려가시겠어요?
From here?
여기에서?
Wait.
기다리다.
It's 9.8km to the hospital from here.
여기서 병원까지는 9.8km입니다.
That's a distance we can run, right?
그 정도면 우리가 달릴 수 있는 거리죠?
But I don't have my running shoes.
그런데 운동화가 없어요.
They're the same design.
그것들은 같은 디자인이에요.
They are.
그렇습니다.
-Are our tastes similar? -Are they?
-저희 취향이 비슷한가요? - 그래요?
Shall we start running then?
그럼 본격적으로 달려볼까요?
Shall we?
우리 할까요?
You look really tired.
정말 피곤해 보이는군요.
Yes.
예.
I did some running yesterday, so I'm really tired.
어제 좀 달리기를 했는데, 그래서 정말 피곤해요.
You should work hard to stay in shape, with your age and all.
몸매를 유지하려면 열심히 노력해야 하고, 네 나이니 뭐니로.
Tell me about it.
그것에 대해 말해주세요.
Right. Dr. Cha, did you know you are the Resident of the Month?
오른쪽. 차 박사님, 알고 계셨나요? 당신이 이달의 주민이신가요?
What?
무엇?
Me?
나?
BEST MEDICAL PERSONNEL OF THE MONTH DR. CHA JEONG-SUK, FAMILY MEDICINE
이달의 최고의 의료인 박사. 가정의학과 차정숙
This is the best.
이것이 최고입니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Do it as fast as you can.
최대한 빨리 하세요.
I have neglected myself.
나는 나 자신을 무시했습니다.
Did you contribute even a single thing to the creation of these assets?
단 한 가지라도 기여하셨나요? 이러한 자산 생성에 참여하셨나요?
Did you not know your wife was ill?
아내가 아픈 걸 몰랐나요?
I don't need your liver.
나는 당신의 간이 필요하지 않습니다.
You should give me at least one chance.
나한테 한 번이라도 기회를 줘야 해요.
It seems Professor Roy has decided to donate his liver.
로이 교수님인 것 같습니다 간을 기증하기로 결정했습니다.
I'm giving her my liver. So why are you butting in here?
나는 그녀에게 내 간을 줄 것이다. 그럼 왜 여기에 끼어들고 있는 겁니까?
Make your choice.
선택하세요.